To describe a neural network in extreme detail for visualization using TensorFlow as a base for a mindmap, let's break it down layer by layer and connection by connection. We'll also highlight key components, functions, and concepts involved in its creation.

### Input Layer
- **Nodes**: x_1, x_2, x_3, \dots, x_n
- **Description**: Each node in the input layer represents a feature in your data. These features can be numerical values, images, texts, etc.
- **Connections**: Each input node connects to every neuron in the first hidden layer.

### Hidden Layers
- **Layer Structure**: The number of hidden layers and neurons within each layer is configurable based on the complexity of the task.
- **Activation Function**: Each neuron in a hidden layer applies a non-linear activation function (e.g., ReLU, Sigmoid, Tanh) to the weighted sum of its inputs.
- **Weights and Biases**: Each connection between nodes has an associated weight, and each neuron has a bias term that modifies the output.
- **Forward Propagation**: The output of each neuron is calculated and propagated to the next layer.

### Example Hidden Layer Configuration:
#### First Hidden Layer
- **Neurons**: h_{11}, h_{12}, h_{13}, \dots, h_{1m}
- **Weights**: w_{ij} (weight from input node x_i to hidden neuron h_{1j})
- **Biases**: b_{1j} (bias for hidden neuron h_{1j})
- **Activation Function**: ReLU (Rectified Linear Unit)
- **Output Calculation**:
   h_{1j} = \text{ReLU}\left(\sum_{i=1}^{n} (w_{ij} \cdot x_i) + b_{1j}\right) 

#### Second Hidden Layer
- **Neurons**: h_{21}, h_{22}, h_{23}, \dots, h_{2p}
- **Weights**: w'_{jk} (weight from hidden neuron h_{1j} to next hidden neuron h_{2k})
- **Biases**: b'_{2k}
- **Activation Function**: Tanh
- **Output Calculation**:
   h_{2k} = \text{Tanh}\left(\sum_{j=1}^{m} (w'_{jk} \cdot h_{1j}) + b'_{2k}\right) 

### Output Layer
- **Nodes**: y_1, y_2, y_3, \dots, y_t
- **Description**: Each node in the output layer corresponds to a class label or a regression output, depending on the task.
- **Activation Function**: Commonly used functions are Softmax (for classification) or Linear (for regression).
- **Output Calculation**:
   y_t = \text{Activation Function}\left(\sum_{k=1}^{p} (w''_{kt} \cdot h_{2k}) + b''_t\right) 

### Loss Function
- **Description**: Measures the difference between the predicted outputs and the actual targets.
- **Common Loss Functions**:
  - Mean Squared Error (for regression)
  - Cross-Entropy Loss (for classification)

### Optimization
- **Algorithm**: Typically, Gradient Descent or its variants (e.g., Adam, RMSprop) are used to minimize the loss function.
- **Backward Propagation**: Calculates gradients of the loss function with respect to weights and biases, and updates them to minimize the loss.

### Visualization with TensorFlow
- **TensorFlow Libraries**:
  - `tensorflow.keras.models.Sequential`: For building a sequential model.
  - `tensorflow.keras.layers.Dense`: For adding dense (fully connected) layers.
  - `tensorflow.keras.optimizers.Adam`: For setting the optimization algorithm.
- **Example Code**:
  ```python
  import tensorflow as tf

  # Define the model
  model = tf.keras.models.Sequential()

  # Input layer and first hidden layer
  model.add(tf.keras.layers.Dense(units=64, activation='relu', input_shape=(n,)))

  # Second hidden layer
  model.add(tf.keras.layers.Dense(units=32, activation='tanh'))

  # Output layer
  model.add(tf.keras.layers.Dense(units=t, activation='softmax'))

  # Compile the model
  model.compile(optimizer='adam', loss='categorical_crossentropy', metrics=['accuracy'])

  # Visualize the model architecture
  model.summary()
  ```

This detailed description and example code outline the structure, components, and processes involved in creating a neural network using TensorFlow. This framework can be visualized as a mindmap, with each layer, node, and connection represented to provide a comprehensive understanding of the neural network.
